# **Shashank Singh**

# **Frontend Developer**

A Frontend Developer with almost 3 years of experience in web development, working @ **Infosys**. A good coder with a solid understanding of the fundamentals of algorithms, and Application architecture. A creative, quick adapter, and a product enthusiast, driven by innovation and have a passion for solving problems by building product.

Ballia (U.P.), India +91-9473722988 singh.shashank2798@gmail.com

# **Work Experience**

**Infosys** Limited - Senior Systems Engineer

December 2019 - PRESENT

# **Project: User Document-Authorization Portal**

May 2022-Present

- Developing complete SPA with Microsoft Authentication Services, Multi-User Authentication based on User Role, and custom people picker using Microsoft Graph-QL.
- Using **NgRx**, **Observables**, **Routing Guards**, Reactive Form, etc. in the development of the application.
- Tech-Stack: Angular 13, Typescript, CSS, Shui-framework, .Net, Zuora, MSAL Services, MS Azure.

## **Project: Bidding management System**

Jan 2022 - April 2022

- Re-designed and Optimized whole applications, modified architecture and reduced code and bundle size by 20%.
- Efficiently managed a team of 3 system engineers during this project, understood client requirements and implemented Agile methodology in the project.
- Awarded with **Infosys Insta Award** for management and performance.
- Tech-Stack: Angular JS, JavaScript, CSS, Shui-framework, Java, SQL.

#### **Project: Idea Management System**

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

- Developed a 50-page application for 400k users with reusable components with Common Validations, Notifications and HTTP Interceptors, Functions, Directives, Pipes and Services.
- Implemented Ag-Grid table and Ag-Grid graph, added dynamic features like CRUD operation on the row, runtime update of data, and complex calculation, which resulted in decrement of load on the backend.
- Received an early **promotion**, promoted to the position of **Senior System Engineer**.
- Tech-Stack: Angular 10, Typescript, CSS, Angular Material, .Net, SQL, MS-Azure.

## **Project: Employee On-Board Portal**

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

- Created a User-HR chat portal using the features of Mendix and entity-object behaviour
- Worked with Microflows and Nanoflows to apply validations, functions and authentication on the pages.
- Tech-Stack: Mendix

### **Project: Internal Company Projects**

Dec 2019 - Sept 2020

- Worked on Full stack projects Queries & feedback WebApp and Internal Employee Portals, as a trainee.
- Developed complete backend services in **NodeJS** (CRUD operations).
- Tech-Stack: Angular 8, Typescript, CSS, NgPrime, NodeJs, MongoDB.

#### **Skills**

**Programming** - Angular (2+), AngularJS, TypeScripts, NodeJS, JavaScript, Python.

Familiar with - Agile methodologies, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Angular-material, Mendix, SQL, MS-Azure (CI/CD), NgPrime, and AgGrid Library.

#### **Awards**

Infosys Insta Award for management and performance

Infosys Angular Certified Professional.

Infosys Basic Agile Certified Professional.

Mendix Certified Rapid Developer.

Voluntary worked as Head of Management in education startup Discovery Classes, 2019

#### **Education**

**B.Tech** (2015-2019) - **Mechanical Engineering** with **Honors** from PSIT, Kanpur, U.P.

## **Social Links**

